Harry Baines

Mobile: 07949 443583 Email: harryb0905@googlemail.com Website: https://harrybaines.net GitHub: https://github.com/harrybaines

Summary

An articulate, hard-working and skilled data science postgraduate from Lancaster University with two years industry experience as a data scientist for an industry-leading environmental consultancy. I am passionate about data science, machine learning and implementing solutions to complex problems and finding insights in large datasets.

Experience

Data Scientist / Yordas Digital

OCT 2020 - JUN 2022, LANCASTER

- Developed and deployed forecasting models using statistical methods and neural networks in Python to predict the likelihood of regulations and substances updating in the next 3 months.
- Assistant supervisor for two data science student projects (general purpose data scraping and named entity recognition for substance name detection), provided daily meetings and weekly code reviews.
- Created a series of data visualisations and conducted ANOVA tests to analyse the effects of a range of production variables on cheese yield for a local cheese manufacturer.
- Created automation scripts for scraping and storing data from regulatory websites using Selenium, Celery, Postgres and Docker.
- Developed full-stack web applications and APIs using Django and Flask to facilitate authoring Safety Data Sheets.

Data Scientist Intern / Yordas Digital

JUN 2020 - SEP 2020, LANCASTER

- Implemented natural language processing techniques to provide smart search functionality through a series of smart search engine prototypes to search a database of 20,000 complex chemical phrases.
- Worked alongside data scientists, software engineers and regulatory experts in an agile fashion to identify project requirements and received iterative feedback.

Software Engineer / Cassidy and Ashton Architects

JUN 2018 - MAY 2022, PRESTON

 Created, deployed and sold a full-stack web application (PERN stack) to facilitate the entry and management of time records and employee data for 60 employees.

Education

MSc (Hons) Data Science (Distinction) / Lancaster University

OCT 2019 - SEP 2020, LANCASTER

- Worked with 360Giving for a group project where we explored the distribution of 12,000 Co-operative Group grants in the UK using machine learning on the Google Cloud Platform to categorise grants into a set of themes and created data visualisations to gain insights.
- Gained experience with data mining, statistical methods, artificial intelligence, distributed systems, natural language processing and building big data systems.

BSc (Hons) Computer Science (First) / Lancaster University

OCT 2016 - JUN 2019, LANCASTER

- Final year project involved researching and implementing a novel language for smart contracts using Golang to enable autonomous agents to create, express and execute social commitments in a concise format on a Hyperledger blockchain with a CouchDB database.
- Gained experience with web technologies, artificial intelligence, databases and advanced programming concepts.
- Collaborated in multiple programming group projects using the agile methodology.

Skills

- Data Science: statistical modelling, Jupyter Notebooks, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, seaborn, Django, Flask, Selenium, Celery
- Machine Learning: scikit-learn, spacy, scipy, NLTK, regression, classification, clustering, PyTorch, neural networks, PCA
- Languages: Python, R, SQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Golang, LaTeX
- Databases: Postgres, SQLite, MySQL, Redis, CouchDB
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Docker, GCP, AWS, Postman, Microsoft Excel, Continuous Integration, Static Analysis

Awards/Achievements

- Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialization, Coursera (2022)
- Machine Learning Scientist Track (3 courses), DataCamp (2022)
- Data Science masters scholarship (2019)
- First class degree alumni scholarship (2019)
- Deep Learning Specialization, Coursera (2019)
- The Complete Web Developer in 2018: Zero to Mastery (2018)
- First year undergraduate commendation for 'outstanding' overall work (2017)
- A-level computing award (2016)
- The Complete Web Developer Course Build 14 Websites (2015)
- Bronze and Gold Duke of Edinburgh awards (2013, 2016)

References

References are available on request